hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is jar
Mike Kowski and I work with coaches
trainers mentors Consultants to able to
scale their businesses make six and
seven figures online grow their email
lists make everything start to work for
them and so on this podcast I want to
talk about sales and this is a topic
that I think is very important in this
business I think as coaches and mentors
we don't like the idea of selling it
feels ick it doesn't feel natural to us
um because we want to help people and
our focus is on delivering results to
our clients that when it comes to sales
we feel like uh I don't know if this is
natural for me as far as that goes first
off understand that a great coach
probably is not going to be a natural
born salesperson and that's what makes
you a great coach understand if you're
struggling to sell it probably means
that you're actually very good at what
you do and that's something I've
identified hugely is that often times
that the people that are really natural
salespeople they actually don't
necessarily have as much skill at the
coaching side of it in this business
they're just really good at getting
people hyped up about it so but what I
want to address is this okay there's a
skill you can learn when it comes to
sales and you got to do it because I can
look at out there there are people that
have less quality products than you do
that are selling way more of what they
offer and it's just because because they
know how to get people to buy it from
them and so it it's always the case it's
like this even in the music industry the
people with the most music Talent have
no no following they don't have a lot of
fans but the ones that uh have the best
marketing have the most listeners as far
as that goes so that applies in business
is yes you're probably a great coach and
excellent in what you do but there's a
skill when it comes to actually selling
yourself that we have to learn and we
have to grow in now if you want to go
deeper in this my client growth
accelerator program is something that
you need to become a part of we just
scratched the surface on this podcast
about what it takes to be able to get
clients and grow your business but my
accelerator program is where we actually
go into becoming a part of your team
part of your success strategy as
somebody that can work with you to get
you results your advertising your
landing pages your sales copy your sales
pitches and be able to actually turn you
from somebody who's struggling to
getting those real results and so if you
have a chance to join our accelerator
program the client growth accelerator
jump into that it's an amazing
experience you'll love it now you have
to be somebody who is willing to talk
about the stuff that you are selling for
instance I don't do that naturally even
on this podcast the commercial that I
literally just gave in the middle of the
podcast right here naturally that does
not come to me to do something like that
but I'll tell you this when I do
that my sales increase they go up I get
more people I help more people when I am
willing to talk about the stuff that I
do on a consistent basis when I'm not
holding back when I do it with
excitement when I do it
with beyond excitement to the level that
it might be irritating and annoying to
people
and that's where you know you're getting
it right is when you start to feel like
you're doing a little too
much that's when you know you're
actually doing just enough and and
really that's exactly the case for
coaches and mentors is when we feel like
I'm just a little too salesy that's
probably the right amount is right at
that point push just a little bit more
into the salesy amount like if I was
here coaching you in a workout right I
look at a lot of this stuff like Fitness
I look a lot of what we do like a
fitness or a sports coach if if
if you're going like 100
yards and you're like okay that's too
much I want you to go
110 and that's the right amount right
there if you're pushing and you're like
I don't I can't do more just a just one
more rep that's enough when you feel
like this is a little too
salesy okay just a little bit more and
that's the right amount that you want to
do is right there like I I I can say in
my business that's exactly what it is
for me when I've looked at my clients
when I've looked at what gets them to be
successful and you don't have to be like
a s slimy sleazy salesperson that's out
there but you do have to promote
yourself and you do need to talk about
the things that you sell the other thing
is this is your energy has to come
across right and this is the second part
of it when you're selling when you do do
that you actually have to somewhat trick
your brain
into not freaking out about oh this is
too much you need to convince your brain
that that too much is the perfect amount
and that it's actually what people want
to hear because your brain is going to
tell you nobody wants to hear that
nobody wants to hear about this
okay I don't know what that voice is but
you know your brain will convince you of
that and that'll hurt you that'll
prevent you from getting the kind of
clients that you want in your
business and so what we got to do is we
got to we got to be willing
to have people dislike us have people
not feel
comfortable in every conversation that
we have and I'm not talking like when I
say be willing to have people feel
uncomfortable when we sell there's a
certain small percentage of people that
are not going to be comfortable with
that they're going to dislike it let
them because those are the people that
would have never bought from you in the
first place and they're just looking for
some reason to have one foot out the
door to discredit you dislike you and
not listen to
you and yet there's a whole group of
people out there that are willing and
want to become your clients they want to
work with you they want to commit
MIT and yet we're holding back we're
thinking I don't want to be too much I
don't want to talk about what I got for
sale too much I don't want to be too
promotive I just want to deliver value
to people I I I get it I just want to
deliver value to people that's all I
want to
do I was just thinking tonight if all I
do is deliver value to people I make no
money and then my family isn't taken
care of my clients aren't
impacted and I'm not actually doing my
responsibility with what I know how to
do me as somebody with 21 almost 22
years experience in this
industry and and I still get caught up
in
this where I feel uncomfortable aable
talking about what I got for
sale even though it's literally the best
thing my client grow accelerator is
literally the best program that
exists it
is and that's not me that says that that
our clients say that the people that
have gone through it say that they tell
us it is the best program they've ever
been a part of and I put my Blood Sweat
and Tears into making sure that that's
that's true
and yet if I don't talk about it if I
don't sell it if I don't get people in
there to get them results if I buy into
other people's excuses there's another
one if I start getting into the weeds of
other people's excuses with them I won't
make any
money and so the way that you actually
start to sell is you learn most of it is
your energy is what it is most of it is
the that you show up in having
excitement and there's a balance of like
it's like a calm excitement it's kind of
like how I am right here on this video
the way that I am on this podcast right
now is the energy for me and my audience
that I find makes me the most amount of
money it's it's excited it's very
Whimsical it's very natural it's very
nonchalant it's I'm I don't care if I
flub up mess up say it say a mistake
make stutter whatever I'm not trying to
control tayor be perfect right no I'm
just being myself this is this is like I
and I'm super relaxed right now I'm
chill I'm calm but I am excited and I
believe about what I'm talking about and
I have a high energy I'm I'm I'm not
lethargic I have a high
energy now all of us have a little bit
of a different version of that but
here's how I think about it how do you
get when you're truly excited about
something and you're talking to people
about it and that's one of the first
things to do is like to really embody
excitement and belief about what it is
that you offer because if you can come
from that place when you're talking with
people where you
truly care about them and you care about
their results and you believe that what
you offer is the best thing for people
you'll show up differently you'll talk
differently you'll communicate
differently and again sometimes you
might have to trick your brain a little
bit in the beginning to do that cuz it
doesn't come
naturally because it doesn't
automatically come naturally but if you
can do that one of the again the best
ways you can do that is to model
somebody that is really good at that
there's a ton of influencers podcasters
coaches mentors that are out
there listen I'm not the only one that
does what I
do I might have been on the pioneering
track in this industry when when I got
started the people that I worked
with but I'm not the only one that does
what I do and I love that and so like if
there's somebody that's out there and
you like their energy and how they show
up and how they sell and they're
successful because I want you to look at
are they successful financially that's
one of the keys that I look
for are they successful financially
because there's a lot of people with
great content but they're not successful
financially and and and I mean listen
there's especially in the coaching world
um I I can think of a few people right
now that I I like their content but I
have actually sort of distanced myself
from watching their content because I
know they don't make any money and the
more I watch their content I grab on to
that energy a little bit okay whereas if
I start consuming content from people
that I know are making a ton of money in
their business I start showing up in my
business like because it's like we're
hanging out together so I virtually hang
out with other millionaires all day
long on my phone when I'm watching
content when I'm listening if I'm
scrolling my social
media I don't consume content that's
going to rot my brain and and you've
heard this before it's because it dials
your energy in that's why I do it now I
have I honestly like I love consuming
brain rotting content I'm going to be
straight transparent and vulnerable with
you on that I do I love it my brain
loves it and it's not healthy for it
because then I don't show up in my best
energy but these algorithms like they're
so good at showing us content that's
going to rot our brain you know it's
like like how television was years
ago what we used to say about television
that's what social media is anyways not
on a tangent about that
but I I pay attention to people that
they're showing up how I want to show up
and by the way the people today that I
listen to are different than the ones
that I listened
to years ago I'll I'll I'll watch people
that I I listened to years ago and I
have a hard time even consuming some of
their content at this point and so again
that's another tangent but when you want
to show up to sell it's about the energy
that you show up with the belief
believing in yourself believing in what
you offer your body language your tone
of voice your facial expressions all of
those go into it and one of the best
ways to sell to people is through video
by connecting and communicating to
people through video if you're
uncomfortable on video I want you to
start making video content 10 20 minute
talks where you're talking maybe once or
twice a week and and start to like
really model and mirror some of the
people that maybe you look up to that
are out there on online and on social
media that's one of the things that I do
as I as I say okay I want to show up
like that energy and then I start to I
want to send those videos out to people
and I want to launch them out there and
I want to get them in front of the right
people and when I do
this I it starts to wire my brain to
operate in that way so again the energy
when it comes to sales is that is that
if you can show up like that in your
advertisements if you can get yourself
into that right State of Mind when
you're writing email marketing this is
one of the things I
find okay I find a lot of coaches they
are creating their marketing materials
their sales pitches their landing pages
their
ads their
emails from a place of
frustration and that literally gets
locked up and embodied in what they're
sending out to people
it
does and so when we can learn how to
actually get ourselves primed into an
excited state of mind into the right
energy for
sales we can
deliver far
better because people will feel
differently about how we show up and how
we talk and how we
communicate and so again it just it has
to do with getting your mind Prim Ed and
tuned to the right State of Mind to the
right frequency kind of like a tuner on
a radio tuning the radio to that place
where you show up best and it does and
it's not striving because if I try to
force myself into that state of mind it
feels forced and it feels cringy and it
feels
yucky but if it's just naturally flowing
out of me like this podcast is literally
like like I am in so much joy right now
emotionally and peace and ease
and like oh I just feel so good right
now recording
this I know that now I'm showing up in
the right state of mind whenever I
record my webinars that's the state of
mind that I also want to get into
whenever I'm writing my email marketing
email is a little different I I can I
can do those in my in my sleep actually
weirdly enough
side note when I write emails sometimes
I like to take a quick nap and then
write it when I wake up for some reason
they come out a little bit better that
way interestingly enough find what works
best for you and then translate that
into your business it might not be
exactly what works for me but you'll
find your thing and and really start to
break down okay what are the things in
my business that aren't working what are
the things in my business that could be
better and and then start to dial those
in and you'll start to see the changes I
promise you that all right listen share
this with somebody don't keep it to
yourself and make sure you're in my
accelerator program I'll see you soon
talk
[Music]
[Applause]